After we have learned about the depth first search algorithm, let's implement it and to see and later
on in the next video, we are going to make the exercise and job.
So we start by creating that structure node containing and vertex and struct node to that next and create
the node struct node create node method that we will create later on and we will make the struct graph
and number of vertices is and that number visited.
OK.
We need int to store that Two-Dimensional array.
Similarly, we need struct node two stars to store any array of link at last.
These are the struct node at adjacent list and we close the graph structure.
OK, so we have created that node and we have created the graph.
Let's create that DFS algo algorithm.
Start by making a method or returning type void.
And it took into the parameter two things that graph that we are going to make it DFS, that we are
going to follow the FSN print and visit all the the vertices and the end vertex.
Where is the starting point of this graph to start from?
We create struct node adjacent list and representing that there's graft adjacent for and lists and starting
from index lever.
And we create a node temp and graph visit that at index vertex is equal to what?
OK, we print visited and we start printing the first thing as the vertex.
This is very obvious that we start from the vertex, so we print the vertex at the first, while temp
does not equal to null.
We start looping through that connected vertices by creating an interconnected vertex equal to temp
vertex of the temp.
And if the graph visit that Connecticut connected vertex vertex, this is the end that we have created
and that we are going as a counter.
We are near.
We are going to increase it in a certain way that we are going to see is equal equal to zero.
Then again, DFS past the graph and the connected vertex.
Here we use the recursion.
We are calling again the DFS and passing the same graph.
But here it is that the vertex is not that one.
It is at a connected vertex that we have reached.
OK, then stamp equal temp the next.
So we are moving that counter or the temp cursor to the next one.
OK, now let's create A..
This is the method that we have to search for its struct node.
It will return a node.
We create the node, the new node, Malaak size reserved for memory by using the Morlock method and
new node vertex is equal to V and then you node next is equal to none and return.
Then you know, we assign the vertex for the new node and we assign the next pointer to none.
This is why we are creating a new note.
Now let's create a method that creates a graph struct graph to return graph and create a graph.
We start from and vertices as we pass into the parameters that vertices that we are going to add in
that graph.
We start by creating a graph that had previously created the one that struck the graph.
We make an object from it.
And a graph adjacent list, we are using them a look memory allocation method.
And we start by adjacent list and the visited list at the size of and and and the size is tracked note,
respectively.
And we create and set for the for loop.
We start from start from zero to vertices passing through all the vertices and we start inserting the
graph adjacent list at all equal to null and the visit that is equal to zero.
So we are marking all the graph, the newly created graph as visit.
That list is equal to zero because we don't have any visit that nodes or visited vertices as yet, and
we return and that created the graph.
Now let's add the edge between two nodes do vertices void, add edge.
We start by getting that graph as parameter that in source and destination, we have learned about this
the previous video about creating the graph.
So we connect the source destination, using them, using the edge.
So we create and, you know, next nodes equal.
The next of the new node is equal to that adjacent list of the graph at index our C and we will create
them.
OK.
And we add them to their adjacent list at the destination.
This is this method we have left it for in the previous that if so, go back, please and learn deeply
about this.
Printing that graph also, we have talked about it.
We passed a graph that we want to print.
We start from zero vertex v equal to zero and we're less than the number of purchases of the graph.
And we go through of C++ through all the elements and we start making them dumb struck notes and we
start printing what stamp is equal to true.
And that's not equal to no.
If we need to test our program, we will create the structured graph.
We created the graph of four vertices, and we are adding the edge to that graph from zero to one,
the source is zero and one is the destination, so zero and one is connected.
We connect to zero and two now we connect one and two and we connect to end the three.
Now print the graph and DFS depth first search algorithm that graph.
We start from two.
So the vertex here is two.
Starting starting point is two.
So I want from you to to write this code in your second and second pilot, and I want to to comment
in the comments below.
That solution and the output of this algorithm.
So and try to post the video and think about it before we put it into the compiler.
Think about how the main method will execute this code and what is the output before putting it into
the sequence planner and to get the result.
So please wait.
I am waiting your comments below, and let's move to the Java.
Java exercised similar very similar to this at depth first search algorithm.
But in Java, the 90 90 percent is the same syntax.
But we are going to make the objects and the classes much different.
So thank you, guys.
I am waiting.
Your comments.
I'm waiting.
Your review five stars only damage support us and pushing us making new tutorials.
And I want from you to comment below for any recommendation, any suggestions and any thing that you.
It is not clear.
So I am here to help you mastering.